we need to
get rid of duplicate elements in our
array
without specifically removing any one
value
so looking at what our array is
currently you can see that we have one
duplicate value which is three
we have a three at index three and at
the end of our array at index 11.
so this is a good time to look at the
documentation and see if there are any
useful methods
you may notice the unique method
now i'm going to output the return value
of invoking unique on our array
and then on line 10 i'll also just print
the array
and you may notice that these are two
different arrays the return value of
invoking unique on an array
is a new array you can see that that
duplicate 3 is not in this new array
however it did not mutate our original
array
as you can see in the second line of
output
if we want to destructively modify our
original array
we can use the destructive unique method
which has a bang at the end
now these are two different methods
you'll see that in the ruby
documentation
now when we invoke the unique with a
bang on line
9 on our array and output the array on
line 10
we expect to see no duplicates because
this method destructively modified our
array
so here's our original array with the
duplicates removed
if you're unsure about whether a method
is destructive or not
be sure to read the documentation
carefully remember that these methods
unique and unique with a bang are two
different methods
as you'll see in the documentation you
can't simply make any method destructive
by adding
a bang at the end